<topics>
  <!-- ================= GREAT BOSTON FIRE ================= -->
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-great-boston-fire</id>
    <results>
      <!-- 1) The Cairo Daily Bulletin (Cairo, IL) -->
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88074142/1872-11-10/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
THE HUM OF THE UNIVERSE IN FLAMES.
Boston, Nov. 9. Very extensivu con
fiagration is now raging at tho corner of
Hummer and Kingston street, extending
east and west on Kingston street nnd
north and south on Summer street. En
gines aro hauled by band.
LATER.
There is no abatement to conflagration,
it is the most extensivo flro that has viiited
Iioston for twenty years, being in tho solid
dry goods portion of tho city. It has ex
tended entire length of Winthorp square,
which embraces A. T. Stewart's, J. M.
Ucebe's, Anderson, Heath is Co.'s, and
Houghton, Perkins Co.'s stores. No es-
timate of tho loss can bo given, but report
ers say it will go into millions. The
suburban Urn department bus been called
upon. The lire is now at its height. The
buildings nre principally of grunito. A
nortbwt't wind is prevailing. Tho preis
hero call It a second Chicago.
THE riRE STILL KAOINO.
Boston, Nov. 9, II p.m. The lire is
now within two blocks of the Western
Union telegraph office. Operators are
taking up t'leir instruments and preparing
to vacate. Lino men and material have
been ordered to Iioston from adjoining
towns, so that if connection with Now
York is lost, which now seems very
likely, it will probably bo soon rctoroJ,
certainly at an early hour in tbe morning,
if not to-night. The fire has now travelled
half a milo through tho heart of the busi-
ness portion of the city, and Is spreading
with frightful rapidity.
ELEVEN-THIRTY P.M.
'J' ho fire is now progressing towards
Hroad street, having swept both fides of
Summer street to High street and pur-
chase street. Goods are being romoved
from sto'es in every direction in tho vicin-
ity of the fire. Engines havo been tele-
graphed far from Providence, Worcester
and other places.
MIDNWflT.
The flro is moving up Franklin street,
and has nearly reached Howley streot.
Cathedral building, corner ot Devensbiro
and Franklin streets, is on flro, with no
hopes of saving it. The flames are also
spreading on Federal and Congress street!
Every kind of vehicle ii impreued mov-
ing goods. The fire has reached the
Rroad street wharves, South Congreis
street, and vessels are on fire. Hartford
and Erio railroad depot is burned.
TWELVE-THIRTr A.M.
It is feared tho en tiro area from Sum-
ner street on tho south, to Washington
street on tho west, to Milk street on the
north, to tbo water on the east, will be
laid waste. Pearl street has to far es-
caped. Heat it intense.
one o'clock a. VI.
Tbe flames havo reached Washington
street, north of Franklin. The Transcript
building is on Are, alo all tho splendid
granite warofcoiues on Franklin squarct
Winthrop square and vicinity aro burned.
Fears are now entertained that the flames
will sweep everything to State street, If
not further north.
FIRE.
        </text>
      </result>
      
      <!-- 2) "A Second Chicago" from Nashville Union and American (Nashville, TN) -->
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85033699/1872-11-10/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
The City of Boston .In Tlames!
Too Business Streets Swept Awiy
Miles of Granite Consumed.
Blowing in Houses to Stop the Fire.
Several Firemen Killed.
The Fire Still Bagliiff at 4 A. 3k,
And Still Spreading – Savagely.
Boston, Mass., Nov. 9. A very exten-
sive conflagration is now raging at the
corner of Summer and Kingston streets.
There is no abatement in the conflagration.
It is the most extensive fire that has visited
Boston for twenty years, and is in the solid
dry goods portion of the city. It has extended
the entire length of Winthrop square, which
embraces A. T. Stewart's, J. M. Beebe's,
Anderson, Heath Co., and Houghton, Terklns:
Co.'a stores. Reporters say it will go into
millions. The fire is now at its height. The
buildings are principally of granite; a northerly
wind is prevailing. The press here call it a
second Chicago.
The fire is now within two blocks of the
Western Union Telegraph Office. Operators
are taking up their instruments and preparing
to vacate. Material has been ordered to Boston
from adjoining towns. The fire has traveled half
a mile through the heart of the city, and is
spreading with frightful rapidity.
        </text>
      </result>
      
      <!-- 3) "THE GREAT CALAMITY." from The Sun (New York, NY) [First version] -->
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1872-11-11/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
THE GREAT CALAMITY.
The Finest "Warehouses and Richest
Parts of Boston in Ashes,
FIFTEEN HOURS OF TERROR.
Losses estimated between $80,000,000 and $90,000,000,
with additional losses of $10,000,000 to $12,000,000.
SEVERAL LIVES LOST.
A plain and unvarnished account of the disaster,
Reception of the news in New York City.
Boston, Nov. 10 – The city has been plunged
into chaos as seventy acres of buildings are consumed.
Nearly every structure in the affected boundary,
stretching along Slimmer and Federal streets to Drake's
wharf, has been obliterated.
        </text>
      </result>
      
      <!-- 4) "THE GREAT CALAMITY." from The Sun (New York, NY) [Expanded version] -->
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1872-11-11/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
THE GREAT CALAMITY.
(Expanded Account)
A catastrophic fire has reduced much of Boston to ashes,
with immense warehouses, rich dry goods, and precious
merchandise destroyed. Losses are estimated between
$80,000,000 and $90,000,000, with additional real estate and
merchandise losses bringing the total further upward.
The article details the rapid spread of flames and the
devastation of the business district, as well as the ensuing
financial panic.
        </text>
      </result>
      
      <!-- 5) "THE FIRE-FIEND IN BOSTON" from The Daily State Journal (Alexandria, VA) -->
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85042224/1872-11-11/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
THE FIRE-FIEND IN BOSTON
THE HEART OF THE CITY IN ASHES
BURNS FIFTEEN HOURS.
The Postoffice and Sub-Treasury partially burned.
Mansard roofs, granite and iron walls, and wholesale
trade areas have been utterly consumed. A financial
panic is feared as government aid is invoked and cities
like Chicago come to assist.
        </text>
      </result>
      
      <!-- 6) "THE BOSTON FIRE" from The Sun (New York, NY) -->
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1872-11-12/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
"THE BOSTON FIRE" – As reported by The Sun (New York, NY) on November 12, 1872, the flames were checked by the following morning. Seventy acres burned with losses estimated at nearly $100,000,000. The article describes somber scenes in the streets, noting that most insurance companies are expected to cover their losses, and that many of Boston’s old granite buildings were blown up in the blaze. The piece also notes a flurry in Wall Street, highlighting Boston's resilient spirit and the immediate relief efforts.
        </text>
      </result>
      
    </results>
  </topic>

  <!-- ================= BELLE GUNNESS MURDER FARM ================= -->
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-belle-gunness-murder-farm</id>
    <results>
      <!-- 1) "Police Are Mystified" – Palestine Daily Herald (Palestine, TX), May 6, 1908 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/XXXXXX/1908-05-06/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
…Find Three More New Graves on the Place of Mrs. Belle Gunness Today  
Woman Missing  
Chicago – Special to the Herald – Chicago, May 6. The coroner declared today that he would examine the body of Max Sorenson, the first husband of Mrs. Belle Gunness, to determine if possible the cause of death.  
Fiendish Deeds – La Porte, Ind., May 5 – With five bodies already unearthed, Sheriff Smuizer and Coroner Mack will continue their search tomorrow for other alleged victims of Mrs. Belle Gunness, who, to all indications, was one of the most fiendish murderesses of the century and who was recently killed along with her three children through the burning of her country home one mile northeast of La Porte.  
Of the bodies so far unearthed, two have been identified – those of Andrew Heldgren, a wealthy bachelor of Aberdeen, S.D., and Miss Jennie Olsen, an 11‑year‑old stepdaughter of Mrs. Gunness. The other three bodies are so badly decomposed as to make identification impossible.  
The discovery of the bodies was brought about by the appearance of John Heldgren of Aberdeen, S.D.—brother of Andrew Heldgren—in La Porte, in search of the missing man. With the information that his brother had come to La Porte to wed Mrs. Gunness, having turned over his property to her, he became convinced that his brother had been the victim of foul play.
        </text>
      </result>
      
      <!-- 2) "Federal Authorities Order All Matrimonial Agencies in Chicago Arrested Since Gunness Exposure" – The Paducah Evening Sun (Paducah, KY), May 8, 1908 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/XXXXXX/1908-05-08/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
More Bodies Brought to Light l
Buried on Farm of Female
Blue Beard Near Laporte
IndChicago
Chicago May Sl1nltell States
District Attorney Sims ordered the ar
rest of every manager of any matri
monlal bureau In Chicago following
tho revelations made In connection
with the Gunnesa house of horror
at LaPortc
latorteIllgghig
Illgghig III Chicago
The police department today began
diggmg In the yard of the place occu
pied J y Mrs flounces while she lived
here at 618 Alma street t expecting to I
end bodies It Is bsiloved she prac
tired her profession here
Chicago May 8Mrs Belle Gun
ness of nportc l Ind bought her
poisons In Chicago
She wns positively Identified from
several of her pbotosrapliH and her
official description as a woman who
was frequently seen In the neighbor
hood of Wubash avenue and Harrison
street us recently as four months ago
and who attempted t1 l purchase mor
phine In u drug store at No 309 Wn
burti avenue
avenueMor
lore HiHllcH Found
Iaporte Ind May 8Shorll nf
tar tho search for bodies burled nt the
Gunmss farm was resumed today an
ether skeleton making the tenth on
earthed since Tiu eday was discovered
It I Is Impassible to determine the sex
of tho victim Another confuted
maw or bones was found later The
sheriff believes the gravo contains two
bodies Decomposition has gone so
far It Is difficult to tell whether there
are one or two bodies In the grave
Several bones of another body were
found shortly before noon two foist
from thoeo first found today This
makes three bodies uncovered today
and twelve since Thiirmlay
Ilrsldn the last Imnch I of bones
which showed burns sips a nictnl
frame of a womans pocketbook All
efforts are being made today to find
the skull of the woman body In the
ruins tr the house Ashes In the cel
for are to be screened In the jPort to
find rome part of tho skull
MaxFon a farm hand rays Mrs
GunncsM had planned to have a power
garden this year on the coot hlo
most of the bodies were found
The first skeleton lay In n wooden
box thrle feet under the surface
Other bones arc a few feet jt wny A
pair of womans shoes were In the box
They were heavy fart l of the shoos
were burned Some bones showed
signs of lire The body In Iho box
had been dismembered exactly In the
same way ns thaw pond before Dig
        </text>
      </result>
      
      <!-- 3) "Tale of Horror" – The Times and Democrat (Orangeburg, SC), May 8, 1908 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/XXXXXX/1908-05-08/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      
      <!-- 4) "Lured to Death by Love Letters" – The Washington Herald (Washington, DC), May 10, 1908 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/XXXXXX/1908-05-10/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
Belle Gunness hereabouts titan th by saying sayingthat aylngthat sayingthat
that that when it was announced at nightfall nightfalltoday nlghtfaIltoday nightfalltoday
today that no more bodies had been dug dugup dugup iugup
up in that garden gard ot death on the Gun Qtnvnese GunnS Gunne
nese nS ne place everybody in Laporte was sur surprises surprhie surprie
prises prisesAlways prhieAlways prieAIwys
Always in her lifetime Jl etlnae suspected and andfeared andfred andfenred
feared the woman has now ow become in the thepublic thepublic thepublic
public mind a perfect paragon of blood bloodlust blCHdluI b1odILt
lust luI craft and nd treachery Apparently Apparentlynobody Atp Anparentinobdy re Uy UyO
nobody O Y would be surprised to leant that thatevery thate thatevery
every e lT square yard of r her ie ftftyacre farm farmis farmIs frrnI
is I sown with the bodies bod of her victims victimsMeantime victimMeantime vlctfmeMelLtIme
Meantime where is Belle Gunness Are Arethose Aretboe Aree Arefragments
those fragments of a female body that thatlie UNitlie thatHo
e
lie in the morgue charred past recogni recognition recognition rognition
tion tion really hers hers or are re they tbetthe the remains remainsof rem remainsof Ju Juor
of some one more of t her beclettms victims fJetIIM intended intendedto
to throw dust in the th eyes of the police policeuntil policeunUI policeuntil
until the multimurderer multlmu er makes good her herescape herI herescape
I
escape pe
Mystery Mystor Is 1 Xot ot Cleared ClearedThere ClenrctlThere ClearedLbsre
There are so many drcumwances to tosupport toqpport toiPPOrt
support iPPOrt either theory that the case re remains re remains reflalns
mains today ae mysteriof myeter1uas ae it was last lastTuesday JutTueadQ lastTuesday
Tuesday when the murder garden yielded yieldedup yieldedup Yieldedup
up its first grim fruit fruitMeanthna fruitMIDtfma fruitManthnn
Meanthna certain things thIa stand nd out as asfacts astacbrhanl astactsbax1
facts tacbrhanl hard and brutal facts that cannot cannotbe e JlltOtbe rnwt rnwtbe
be explained expl led away awaySince awarSlnca awaySince
Since little Dun Hudson and ad Joe Max Maxson Muson Maxson
son got to work with their pinks and andspades andspades I
spades spad five day days ago they ha hevs re dog d g ap apwhat wPbat upwhat
what bat the doctors s y are re tile remnants reeinan of often otlen often
ten human hoW bodies bodiespit bodiespour I IlWr
pour of them Wit Jit 1 1lilt laj lajpit
pit about tour 1ty byOnly ay s vfyft vfyftOnly it itOnly
I I1Itd
Only three of them have been identi identified identifled
fled with any certainty The first was wasAndrew wasAndrew wasAndrew
Andrew K Ii I Heigelltn HIiIU a mWdJesged Nor Norwegian Norwectan Norwegtaii
wegian lured from his home botM at Alter Aberdeen Alterdeen Aerdent
deen S Dak by the expectation of mar marriage marriare marrIie
riage with the welltodo widow widowTh wtdowThe widowThe
Th The second was as O C Budsberg an anelderly anelderly 11 11elderly
elderly farmer from lola Wis The same samebait amebait samebait
bait brought him to his death The last lastof Jutof lastof
of the three identified J nttled bodies was Jennie JennieOlson JennieOl8on JennieOlson
Olson an eighteenyearold ei bteenJear I girl and od the theadapted theadeptH thede
adapted de daughter of Delta GtaRn ua tunasua a All AJ1the Allthe 1 1tbe
the remaining six whose ho bodies bod this tb tr trrinla tar11b18 tsrriNe
rinla little garden has yielded were men menwith menwith
4 with a single sinr exception and when that that1s thatis
1s 1 said sal ia all that is known of them has hasbeen basbeen hasbeen
been stated
statedAH
AH Ten ici Are Slain SlainThat SIuluThat SlainThat
That all ten of these were murdered murderedthere murderedthete murderedthere
there IB no doubt As 4 to the four whose whosebodies whoHbodies whosebodies
bodies were found foa buried beneath the theruins theruins theruins
ruins of the house on the morning of ofApril ofApril ofArt1
April 28 2S there is some doubt Three of ofthem orthem ofthem
them were children of this JJueretta Bor Borgia Borgia Borgte
gia of Laporte Laportetwo two girls and a boy boyMyrtle boyMyrtJe boyMyrtle
Myrtle aged a eleven Lucy nine and andPhilip andPbllip andPhilip
Philip five In the identity of the fourth fourthlies fourthlies fourthlies
lies the solution of t the problem problemMurder problemurder problemMurder
Murder urder for revenue only was apparent apparently
j ly the passion that consumed Belle BII Gun Gunness GunneaL Ginacm
ness That several of her victims were werepersons werepersons werepersons
persons from whose death she could got gotprofit getprofit gotprofit
profit in a pecuniary p way in no man manner manner mannet
ner controverts c ntrover8 this statement In every everycase everycue everycase
case of wholesale murder there have hll been beensome bMnsome beensome
some victims who died because their theiralienee theirstlen theirsilence
silence stlen e was deemed more precious than thangold thangold thangoki
gold In such a position Jennie J nne Olson Olsondoubtless 0150ndoubUea Olsondoubtless
doubtless found herself This adopted adopteddaughter lutOptOOdaughtfr nooptoddaughter
daughter was a simpleminded quiet girl girlwho girlwho girlwho
who was known to the neighbors Jlet bors chiefly chieflybecause cbiefi30auae chieflybecause
because auae she did more work than any anyhired anyhired anyhired
hired man She was liS BoDe Gunness pret pretty pretty pretty
ty slave And yet the mistress feared the theslave Utelave theslave
slave lave So the slave died and vs buried buriedin burledIn buriedin
in quicklime in the same death garden gardenthat gardenthai gardenthat
that had received the bodies of others otherswho othersr otherswho
r who died because they had money moneyNot moneyNot moneyNot
Not Attractive Personally PersonallyWhat Pcronnllyat PersonallyWhat
What at sort of woman was this Astound Astounding stoundlug
in lug murderer That is a hard question questionand questfoand questionand
and yet something can be done toward towardanswering towardaDIIWertDl towardanswering
answering She Sh was a Norwegian who wholacked wholacked wholac
lacked lac ed about two years of the halfcen halfcentury haItcentury halfcontury
tury mark She Sb was born in Norwayf1MI Norway Norwayend Norwayand
end came ean to America as a young girl In InMocfo InQqo Inhi
Mocfo Qqo m In uji she married Max l x Soren Sorenson Sorenson Sorenson
son fellowcountryman He died sud suddenly suddenly cuddenly
denly In UM UMTwo 1MTwo IISOTwo
Two years later she married Gunness GunnessHe GunnessHe GunnessS
S He also died suddenly as will be seen seenDeath sennt
t 1 Death De th sudden and mysterious attended attendedBelle attend attendedBells d dBelle
Belle dimness for many years When Whenshe Whenshe Whenshe
she came to Laporte six years ago with withGunnesfi withGo withOjinnees
Go Gunnesfi nn ees Mrs Gunnass was a a fat coarse coarsefeatured coareefeatured coarsefeatured
featured woman who stood about five flvofeet tlvofeet fivefeet
feet seven and nd welShed about 230 pounds poundsShe poundsShe poundsShe
She had a big heavy head a mop of ofcoarse ofeoarse ofcoarse
coarse hair of a muddy brown little eyes eyesthat ayestbat eyesthat
that just missed being black huge hands handsand handsand handsand
and arms but feet grotesquely small for forthe forthe forthe
the burden burd n they they had to o support Every Everybody Everybody Everybed
body bed who knew her agrees that she was wasffcr wasfar wasfar
far from attractive attractiveMost attractlnMost attractiveMost
Most of her acquaintances desorlbe her heras herf heras
f as repulsive repulsiveSomo Some of her neighbors go gofurther gofurther gofurther
further Moro a devil than a woman Wmanwas womanwas womanwas
was the way William Desslelen put it itand 1t 1tand itand
and he ought to know because bis hlstarm hlstarmis farm farmis
is next to tho Gunness place placeCordial placeOortllal placeCortIlal
Cordial at First Only OnlyMy OnlyMy OnlyMy
My aunt was always a strange strangewoman strangewoman strangewoman
woman her nephew John Lawson told toldthe toldtile toldthe
the police 1 the other day When you youfirst yoUfirst youfirst
first knew her she would be very V ry cordial cordialThen cordialThen cordialThen
Then she would get offish offishShe offishShe oflishShe
She has alweys been offish to say the theleast theleast theleast
least in Laporte Her home for years yearsContinued yoorS yoorSontln yearContinued
Continued ontln ed on Pope 3 Column S SSome SSome 5Some
Some lumber firms 1Jrm say ay times vrlUBooa vrlUBooabe wlUsoobe 11100 11100be
be better and are holding up pricea prl prIccsh
h
0
THE THER9LL ROLL OF DEATH DEATHIN DEATHIN DEATHIN
IN THE GUNNESS CASE CASEFeJteving CASEFelleMn CASEFellewin
FeJteving Fellewin u is the roster of bodJes BO far farfound farfo farf
found f d at the t e murder m rdw factory r of Mrs 1rt Gun Gunness Gunneeta Gunne5
ness neeta ne5 IB Laporte Ind IndMYRTLE IndIYRTL lad3IYRTLB
MYRTLE IYRTL SOUEXSON teed eleren elerendaughter elenDdaUhter eletendaughter
daughter of Mrs In Gunnws burned to death deathin deathIn th thIn
in the Gumesj Gum aa home brcheLUCY homeLUCY borneLUCY
LUCY SORBNSON SORB SON tged red nine joungost joungostdaughter J ouneat ouneatdaughter DfIst DfIstdaughter
daughter ef a Mrs Gmmess who likewise likewisewas Itkew1Jwas ltkewiaaras
was ras burned to death in the fire firePHILIP fi fiPHILIP firePRILIP
PHILIP GUNXfcSS GUNN SS aged fire the son on of ofMra orMu ofMrd
Mra GwneM GIi burned in the destruction of ofthe ofthe ofthe
the Gai GUDeM e house bouseANDREW 1MaueANDUBW houseANDIIIW
ANDREW HBLGELEIN aged fifty fiftybachelor fertrlIae futybatheior
bachelor lIae elor of Aberdeen S S Dak tuitar for ftrMB ferMI8 forMa
MB Onions GI II8M1 bend who came to Laporte LaporteJaiwarj LaporteJanlu LaporteJanuary
January Janlu 5 5 1903 100a I9O and disappeared three vwfcs ueea ueea3aer vwfcskter
kter after drawing J3flQO 3Ocfl from bank bankJENNIE hankJBNNIE bankJSN8E
JENNIE OLSON aged seventeen filnteen daugh daught daugittN
tN t r of Anton Olson of Chicago wham rh a Mrs MrsGvMaasa Mrsteok 1ra 1raOvabeM
GvMaasa teok to alas vltea eight years 8US of ofage ofa ofOLE
age a
ageOLE
OLE 014 B BUDSBERG who came from fromIota fromJoIa frernlola
Iota Wk about a year ago in answer to toa toa toa
a matriiwatel mairim rnatr nenisl l adratfceoynt adrertJ5e nt aad wbe he drew drewJl drewfrem drewL5O
Jl L5O DO fi horn m t6 borne bask baakUaUwttiM 1MaIlLU baskUnitlintifiM
UaUwttiM U l body headless of a raman ramansupposed ImnADMIfPtSed wetmamicesed
supposed at that to be Mrs GtiffittM Ou telt teltwfciab ttwld t twhi
wfciab wld nay rne be th tile body of a tlqtlm glaced glacedto J ared aredto ed edto
        </text>
      </result>
      
      <!-- 5) "Fifteen Victims Die in Big Murder Plot" – Valentine Democrat (Valentine, NE), May 14, 1908 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/XXXXXX/1908-05-14/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
Finding of Nine Bodies in Yard
Reveals Mysterious Whole
sale Killings.
WOMAN CALLED A BLTJEBEAED
Supposed Death of Herself and Chil
dren in Fire Only Adds to
the Puzzle.
Wholesale murder murder more
ruthlessly premeditated and diabolical
ly executed than the famous Holmes
castle crimes in Chicago was revealed
at Laporte Ind. Tuesday when five
mutilated bodies were dug up in the
back yard of the home of Mrs. Bella
Gunness who together with her three
children are supposed to have met
death when their house burned one
week before.
Fifteen persons already have a place
on the list of known or probably slain
and circumstances point to Mrs. Gun-
ness as the arch-conspirator in at least
twelve of the crimes. Until this time it
i had been accepted as true that she and
j her three children had met death in the
fire that destroyed their home but now

the suspicion arises that the bodies that
p
were found in the smoldering ruins
were brought from some hospital or
medical school for the purpose of cre-
j ating the belief that Mrs. Gunness and
her family had pas.sed from existence.
Ijixt of l\uo\vii A'iotims.
ITclgoloin. Andrew 40 years old. bach
elor. Aberdeen S. D. suitor for Mrs.
Guunoss hand who came to Laporto in
January and disappeared ono mouth later
after loaning the woman $1.500 body
dug up to-day.
Gunness Jennie Olson. 16 years old
adopted daughter of Mrs. Gunness disap
peared in September IfXKi. ostensibly to
attend school at Los Angeles body dug
up to-day.
Unidentified man believed by Sheriff
Smul/cr to have been an admirer of the
woman.
Unidentified boy. apparently 8 years
old mutilated body in gnnnysack.
Unidentified girl about 7 years old
mutilated body in gunnysaek.
Gunness Joseph husband of Mrs. Gun-
ness whose death at Laporte four years
ago had always remained a mystery.
Sorensen Mads woman's first hus
band who died under mysterious circum
stances in Chicago eight years ago.
Gunness Mrs. Bella believed to have
been burned to death in fire which de
stroyed lier home.
Sorensen Myrtle. 11 years old eldest
daughter of Mrs. Gunness thought to
have perished in the fire.
Sorensen Lucy Q years old another
daughter also believed to have been a
victim of the fire.
Gumiess. Philip 5 years old. youngest
child said to have been killed in the tiro.
Lindblom. Olaf. 35 years old. of Wis
consin employed by Mrs. Gumiess on the
farm. When ho. disappeared Mrs. Gun-
ness gave it out that he had gone to
Norway.
Gorhalt Eric. 40 years old. of Wiscon
sin worked five months for Mrs. Gun-
ness then he disappeared.
Man from Ohio. 50 years old. name
not learned worked on the farm and
owned a horse and buirny. Dis-appoarod
and Mrs. Gunness fell heir to the horse
and buggy.
la the arrest of liay Laniphere a
CHRONOLOGY OF INDIAHA
JrlULTI-MUKDER MYSTERY.
Mads Albert Sorensen Austin. 111. dies
mysteriously V.OO His widow col
lects $8,500 insurance.
Candy store at Kli/.aboth btreet and
Grand avenue. Chicago owned by Soron-
sons burns. Insured.
Two peculiar files in Austin home. In
surance collected.
Widow marries Joe Gumiess- Moves
to Laporto farm. Adopts Jennie ONn
Gumiess killed (1001) Widow s.i\
meat ck-aver fell on his head. Collo'-ts
o,500 insurance.
Ray Lamphere goes to work for Mrs.
Guiltless as hired man.
Widow sets dogs on visitors.
Neighbors see lanterns on farm n 2
a. in.
Jennie Olson disapprs. Real pircnts
are told she is in Ix s Angeles school but
can not find her J1KXJ
Andrew llolgelein Aberdeen S. 1)
aii-swors matrimonial ad and arrive.t
Laporte farm. Loans Mrs. Gunncs 1.-
500. Disappears with like amount in
pockot. Widow says lie wont to Noiw i\
Mrs. Gunnevj HT tolls shonff
strange man killed a child in woods near
farm. Sheriff finds only empty gra\
Ray Lamphere arrested for annoing
Mrs. Gunnels.
Widow tells lawyer April 251 tint
Lamphi'ie intends to kill her. Draws up
will.
Home burns April I'.G. Bodies of thro
children and headless woman found in
ruins.
Lamphere arrested in hollow tiv. h d
in r.
M.iA. K. ib-it'li in Im i- li ill- of
brother bunod near hoii o. Jennie 'SCM\
body also found.
Nine unidentified bodies of men and
ihihlron are found buried near house.
Most bodies lie on mattresses under four
feet of earth.
May j. Joe Ma\soii. farm hand tolls
police he dus holes on orders of Mrs.
Gumiess. but never filled them.
J-Xpres mon toll jx lko of mysterious
arrhal at farm of many bis trunks.
former servant of the woman. Sheriff
Smulzer believe some liirht may be
thrown upon the circumstances sur
rounding the deaths of at least some
of the victims.
Lamphere before the fire had trouble
with Mrs. Gunnos.s. Uo had declared
about town she was trying to "iret rid"
of him because he knew too much. He
has told several conilictini stories
concerning his relation with the wom
an and his presence in the neighbor
hood of the Gunness home the night it
burned.
The discovery of the Ixnlies led ex-
pressim'ii to tell of the delivery of five
trunks to the Guiines-s farm during the
last six months. This fact has caused
the authorities to incline to the theory
that the place may have been a "clear
ing-house" for murders. They suspect
that wealthy person after being lured
to Chicago and killed may have l een
packed into thc-c trunks sent to La
porte and disjio etl of there. Lamphere
in his cell declared Mrs. Gunness fre-
nivntly asked him to buy poison for
her. She wanted chloroform he said.
Four of the bodies were found buried
in a refuse pile about 150 feet from the
house while another body was duir
up within a few teet of the ruined
home. It is he opinion of Coroner
Mack and physicians who examined the
bodies that th 'y were burned after
death. Ilelirelein was easily identified
by his brother although the remains
had been badly mutilated. The body
of the other man show- red mustache.
The discovery of the bodies primarily
was due to the efforts of Mr. llelge-
        </text>
      </result>
      
      <!-- 6) "Murderess" – The Stark County Democrat (Canton, OH), May 22, 1908, Weekly Edition -->
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/XXXXXX/1908-05-22/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
Acting on
private information, Mayor Darrow, of
counsel for Ray Lamphere, who will
be indicted for the murder of Mrs.
Belle Gunness and her three children
and Andrew Helgoleln, of Aberdeen,
S. D tonight entered Into communi
cation by cable with the police ot
Scotland Yard, London, and the au
thoritles in Canadian cities, advising
ttKsm of tho reward of $1000 which
will be paid by Laporte county for tha
finding of tho murdeiess Following
his declaration that tho teeth Identi
fied as those of Mrs. Gunness are in
too perfect condition to have been In
the fierce blaze which destroyed the
head, and charred, baked and burned
the rest of the body, Mayor Darrow,
also took steps to consult with experts
upon whom he relies to disprove tho
identification of tho teeth. Coronor
Mack added the weight of his opinion
that Mrs. Gunness' body was that
found In the ruins of tho charnel
house when ho tonight officially de
clared: "It is my verdict that the body su
viewed is that of Belle Gunness; that
she camo to her death through felon
ious homicide; and that the perpetra
tor thereof Is to me unknown."
Coroner Mack says that so far as
Andrew lfelgelein, of South Dakota;
Ole Budsberg, of Iola, Wis and Jen
nie Olson, the adopted daughter ot
Mrs. Gunness, aro concerned his ver
dict will be that their bodies wero
properly Identified, that they came tn
their death from unnatural causes,
that they were burned to cover up
murder and that Mjrs. Gunness had a
motive for killing them and was guil
ty either alone or with accomplices
of murder.
Mrs. Henry WItzer of Toledo, walk
ed among the dead at the morgue this
morning hoping that there might bo
somo mark of identification on onn of
the skeleton forms which would prova
that her daughter was one of the vic
tlms of the house of tragedy. Tears
rioursed down tho mother's cheeks as
she looked upon the headless and dls
membered bodies. There was no Iden
tification, but the Toledo woman, hop.
ing that some tragedy might solve
the mystery of her daughter's strange
disappearance, came to Laporte like
scores of others, In the hope that the
Gunness murders would unfold th3
mjstery which she has vainly labored
to solve since 3902, when Frances
Witzler, young and pretty, a college
graduato with life before her, left
her home never to return.
Mrs. Witzler believes her daughter
met death in the charnel house.
The grand jury is making splendid
progress In the taking of evidence.
Theie is a disposition on the part of
the stato's attorney, Smith, to conclude
the labors of tho body of inquisition
not later than Friday, when the 'ndict
ments against Ray Lamphere w '11 un
doubtedly be returned.
With tho reading of tho Swedish
committal service tho skeleton of Jen
nie Olson, was this afternoon lowered
Into a grave at Patton's cemetery.
The plot of giound in which she lies
adjoins tho burial place of Andrew
Helgoleln.
Dr Martin received tort? from
Washington a letter descrlb o. wo-
.id be.
TWO DAY TICKETS
TO
1
3 T3jR.fjHJ' TKP- 5
JJk I
ash nit: whcvumij.
EVERY SATURDAY AND SUNDAY.
T&0 ROUND
JB.I
man seen on tne street in'
lioved'by tho writer to b -4 o. Gun
ness. The man does .five his
name, but says he saw oman ho
describes on tho oven y if May 13,
at 15th stivet and .cot, before
he ever saw a pictu o tho l-aporte
murderess. ij
Attorney Worde the defense, la
still a firm bolievei tho theory that
Mrs. Gunness made her escape. Ho
claims tha a woman to thoroughly
ei&ed with the instincts of criminal
ity, as she, would resort to such!
means of diverting suspicion "She
could very easily havo a dentist re
movo those plates from her mouth,"
ho declares, "and leave thorn as sho
left tho lings, near the bodies found
In" tho basement ot her house."
The searching of tho debris today
brought another gold ring to light.
It bears the initials "S. B., May 28,
1907," and It may prove a factor in
solving the identltv of another body.
States Attorney Smith stated to
night on emerging from tho ;rand
Jury room that he would ask for tho
lndlrtment of Ray Lamphere on six
counts. Four for the murder ot Mrs.
Gunness and her three children, ono
us accessory in tho Wiling of Andrew
Helgeleln and one for arson.
        </text>
      </result>
      
      <!-- 7) "Mrs. Belle Gunness of LaPorte's Murder Farm" – Crittenden Record-Press (Marion, KY), May 28, 1908 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/XXXXXX/1908-05-28/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
RAY LAMPHERE, WIDOW GUNNESS' FARM HAND.
Hay I.ainphere under arrest (it LuMrte, lud on suspicion of U'lng concerned
Iij tin burning of tliu farmhouse of Mrs. Belle Gtinness nnd the murder
of the Gunnes children nnd tlielr mother, formerly wns employed us ii fnnn
baud by the Widow Ounness. It Is ulleged thnt he made love rli her nnd wn
repulsed, Mrs. Ounness twlng on the trull of men with money who were
Vengeance and Jealousy an- alleged an motive for burning
the house and destroying the fnmll.v Lniuphere stoutly asserts his Innocence
nnd declare that lie "always thought there was something wrong at
that place." inetttdng the Outlines fann He toltl the authorities thnt aUmt
two yenn ago a large man caiue to the farmhouse who was wild by Mr.
Gunnes to lx) a BUltor for the hand of her adopted daughter. Jennie Olsen,
and flint he never kneu uhnt Uiiwie uf the man. Miss Olson's tvly w:im
one f Uhm found burled n the premium, along with eight others. When
CHiiitht I jiii phetv wrm hiding In a hollow tree.
t
X
RUINS 0? GUNNESS HOUSt, LAFORTE.
I'ie inrinliiui of Sirs Belie Gtmtic a n.i e frem Luporte. Iml., was
totally destroyed by lire on the night of April 1!7 This lire led to the discovery
of the nine IhmIIos of munler tlrtlms burled on the premises and developed a
crime mystery which linn horrllled the nation. The house was built of brlok,
with an addition built of lumber. Joseph Muxson, the hired man, slept In n
room nlKivM the wooden kitchen, nnd he says thnt lie nuoke nlniiit -1 o'clock
In the timmlui; stlilel by smoke which was pouring out of the brick part of
the house He tried to enter thnt pnrt but could not. Several neighbors who
arrived shortly nIo were driven back by tlntnes The charred bodies of
three children found In the ruins were IdeiitlllHl as thoce of Mrs Guntiess.
while the Ixxly of a woman, from which the head was missing, either burned
off or decapitated prior to the fire, wap believed at first to be that of Mrn.
(Junnosi. Kulweiiuent disclosures ns to the "murdt r farm" lead some to
believe thnt Mm. (jiinness plnccd the headless trunk of n murdered woman
In the house to serve nn a blind In effecting her own escne from Justice.
w
JOStrt, .viAaSON, WHO WAo EMPLOYED BY MRS. GUNNESS,
Josupti Muxhon, who was employed ab man of all work around tho house
and farm of Mm. Helle Ounness near Luporte, lud., poluted out to the authorities
certulu Hpots In the yard of the burned farmhouse where, he said, he hud
bceu Instructed by Mrs Gutfliesa from tlmo to time to deposit such rubblah
ns was to be thrown nway. The nine bodies of persons supposed to bur
Oecu murdered by Mrs. dunness were dug up at points Maxson Indicated.
-Jl
T l" i-
tH .ii.)-"
HH9t$M sis1
MI. I MI tfysi
BWPBBff StEP Wf;. fWp 'iff j&mKk 4
UVKKSKmi
K0&J;fcl2?imfij
nntHjiUM
Bw 1ft
iBofH
ASSv VT7"
rag
SS24"
18? KUCKilg r"
3
'v&3 ossa a
MRS. BELLE GUNNESS, OF LAPORTE'S MURDER FARM.
Mrs. Jlelle Ounness, tho widow mispWed of the murder of the persons
whose iKvlles were dug npffroui Uio premlsi of her burnwl home n mile from
Luporte. IntL, waa n Norwegian woman whoso mnltlen name was Tnulson.
She was married first to Mar SorwiHcn, who died under suspicious
Her second husband. Philip Ounness, dlisl under similar
It wnfl'reiwrted at first that the body of Mrs. Ounness was found
with thoso of her threo children In the ruins of her houses. The head of tho
charred remains of tho woman found in the rulas was missing, which fact
caused the Authorities to suspect that Mrs. Ounness herself hnd killed her
children nnd set tire to tho dwelling after placing In the house the decapitated
liody of one of her ndult women rlctlms in nn effort to cause the belief
that sho had perished in the fire. Mrs. Ounness hnd lind an enormous quantity
of gold work done on her teeth The grewsome mystery of the missing
head, It was said by those who held the theory of the flight of Mrs. Ounness,
was explained by the woman's r t! :it 'o left her substitute's head on
the body It would be evident thai k..o her- s not a victim of the fire.
til ''?t
I
IP Ct' v?lK iV'eisJKf.
If 1 Sff
It,9 I Vvife ',mM
IIHwl& vtfHilsEtiyBB
STATE
AT"iu.... ..Of U.
SMITH.
V
f
ANDREW HELGELEIN, ONE OF MRS. GUNNESS' VICTIMS.
One oi tie ...e uhiIi.s disinterred from the premises of Mrs. Belle Ounness,
near Luporte, lud., wns Identllled as thut of Andrew llelgeleiu, a wealthy
stockman of Aberdeen, S. D., forty yours of age. Ho wus a Norweglsui, as wiu
Mrs. Ounness. who had advertised for a prospective husband with means.
Helgeleln stnrtetl for Luporte Jan. .'5, since which date nothiug was heard from
him by lib relatives, who were aware that ho hud gone to the Indiana wldowa
home with matrimonial Intentions. It wns known also that he had drawn
$3,000 from his Aberdeen bank account after arriving at Luporte. The theory
Is that Mrs. Gunness killed Helgeleln to get his money.
MRS. GUNNESS AND HER THREE CHILDREN.
Mrs. Ilelle Gunness, the Indiana woman who Is believed by the police to
have lured to her farm home near Laporte several men on mntrlmonlal pre-1
tenses nnd then murdered them for their money, is said to have been qulto
fond of her three little children, whose charred bodies were found In tho ruins
of tho Gunness farmhouse, along with the headless trunk of n woman, who i
was supposed at first to be the body of tlielr mother. The children wero
Myrtle Sorensen, aged eleven, and Lucy Sorensen, aged nine, daughters of
Mrs. Gunness by her first husband. Max Sorensen, and Philip Gunness, aged
five, namesake of his father, who. like Sorensen. Is said to have died under
suspicious circumstances.
DH. C. F. MACK, CORONER, TAKING NOTES.
Shortly after the discovery' of the first bodies that had been burled on the
premises of tho Widow Gunness near Laporte, Ind., Dr. C. F. Mack, the
coroner, arrived on the scene nnd wns busy taking notes for official use. The
nine bodies of murdered men and women dug up In the yard near the ruins of
the burned farmhouse passed under Dr. Mack's close scrutiny, as did also
those of the three children and the woman found In the ruins. A Jury composed
of physicians thoroughly examined the charred remains of the children
nnd the woman nnd arrived at the conclusion that they were those of Mrs.
Belle Ounness nnd her little ones. It wns Impossible to determine the sex of
five of the bodies disinterred, they hnvlng been dismembered and also partially
disintegrated by quicklime. Mr. Mack made copious notes for reference
In future efforts to solve the horrible mystery nnd Identify the victims, most
of whom are believed to have been men who were lured to the place by tho I
matrimonial advertisements of Mrs. Gunness, who described herself as m
rich widow wanting a husband with some money.
JOHN HhLGELEIN, BROTHER Ui- JrJh 0- THE VICTIMS.
Suspicion against Mrs. Belle Ounness was first aroused In Indiana by the
.i,..,i n n.uri,i nt Toim i n n N'orweirinii from Mansfield, S. D.,
who came to investigate the disappearance of his brother, Andrew Helgeleln,
of Aberdeen, S. U. Andrew Helgeleln wus known to hare answered oue of
Mrs. Ounuesa' adrertisements for a husband with money. lie leri Aueruceu
on Jan- 3 to visit Mrs. Gunness nt her home near Laporte. After his arrival
lu Laporte ho had drawn $3.0fX from Ills bnnk in Aberdeen. John Helgeleln,
becoming worried because nothing further was heard from his brother, wrote
to Mrs. Gunness, who replied that Andrew had departed for a visit to Norway.
John Helgeleln Identified we of the first bodies found as that of hH brother.
        </text>
      </result>
      
      <!-- 8) "The La Porte Murder Farm" – The San Juan Islander (Friday Harbor, WA), July 11, 1908 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/XXXXXX/1908-07-11/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text><
          SCENES AT THE GOTNESS "DEATH FARM" HEAB IA POBTE, DTO.
THE LA FORTE MURDER FARM.
There Read
Like a Story- of the Mid-Centuries.
Like a chapter from the bloody rec
ords of the mid-centuries is the ter-
rible story unfolded by the authorities
of La Porte, Ind., where wholesale mur
der was done for years without anyone
knowing or suspecting It. Criminal rec
ords contain nc parallel of the grew
some story revealed in the finding of
the clearing house for murders kept by
Mrs. Belle Gunness near the Indiana
town. Just how many persons met
their fate in connection with the bloody
business carried on there will perhaps
never be known. The skeletons dis
covered on her premises and the fact
that expressmen had many times de
livered to her boxes and trunks now
believed to contain human bodies form
the chief materials for the construction
of the strange story of her career. She
is supposed to have lured rich men to
Jier den by matrimonial advertisements
and then made away with them for
their money, and also to have run a
murder "fence" for the benefit of her
partners in the awful trade of human
slaughter, the latter operating in Chi
cago and sending the bodies of their
victims to her for burial. It is the
theory of the prosecution that Mrs.
Gunness deliberately lured men to
her farm by means of an advertisement
in a Chicago newspaper, in which she
represented herself as an attractive and
amiable widow looking for a mate. She
alleged that she was the owner of a
valuable farm and sought a well-to-do
farmer as a husband. After a visit
from such a candidate she generally in
duced him, it appears, to sell his farm
and come to her with the proceeds of
the sale, at which time she would de
liberately murder him and bury his
Vdy en the premises.
For years this strange woman Is
»«al(1 to have conducted her murder mill.
while her neighbors remarked upon her
good humor and her children mingled
with others of their age in the neigh
borhood. And the end of this record
of. crime and mystery is shrouded In
2*2 JI2I. WIL LIJS/I /TETTER^.
uncertainty. A fire which destroyed
the Gunness borne also disclosed the
fact that her three children had either
been murdered before the fire or that
they had perished in the flames.
In some respects the methods of Mrs.
Belle Gunness seem similar to those
of the infamous Bender family in Kan
sas. Yet it is doubtful if the blood
thirsty Kate Bender in her palmiest
dnjTß was over equal to the awful
crimes that are laid at the door of the
Gunness woman. The story of the La
Porte murder farm recalls the noto-
rioos doings of the Bender family in
Montgomery County, Kan., about forty
years ago, and the famous case of
Henry H. Holmes, who swindled insnr
ino» companies and was held respon-
CHECK. .FHOWIHtf TH»T HLL^rta
P "WITHIXfcEIi/ 2LL OP HIS" S!AVIXt&.
jible for the murder of quite a long list
3f persons. He was hanged in Phila
delphia. The Benders, husband and
wife and son and daughter, were sap.
posed to have murdered nine or tea
persons and buried the bodies In the
vicinity of their home, robbery being
their motive. The Benders mysteri
ously disappeared and their fate is un
known, although rumora were abroad
at the time that Indignant citizens put
an end to their infamous careers.
          /text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>

  <!-- ================== JACK THE RIPPER ================== -->
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-jack-the-ripper</id>
    <results>
      <!-- 1) "British Bits" – Salt Lake Daily Herald (Salt Lake City, UT), November 27, 1888 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/XXXXXX/1888-11-27/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
LONDON November 25rhe steamer
Neiiburgh of Leith while on her voyage
from Gracgermouth to Aarhus with
coal foundered in the North Sea Six
teen persons were drowned and one was
rescued and landed in Norway
A private person living near NottiD2
ham has received a letter signed Jack
Rippers pal stating that both the
writer of the letter and Jack com
mitted the recent murders in White
Chapel district The writer says Jack
is a Bavarian whom he first met
aboard a ship returning from America
and who exercised a mesmerjstic in
fluence        </text>
      </result>
      
      <!-- 2) "Jack, the Ripper" – Sacramento Daily Record-Union (Sacramento, CA), December 18, 1888 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/XXXXXX/1888-12-18/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
"JACK, THE RIPPER."
A Montreal Crank, Who ig Probably a
Ripping Liar.
Montreal, December 17th.—A man has
been arrested here for assaulting a woman,
who says he is "Jack, the Ripper." This
evening, a3 Miss Florier Newcome was
was walking on Lagauchetorie street, in a
dark quarter of the city, a man suddenly
dartea out of a gateway and caught her by
the arm, exclaiming: "You must come
with me!" The girl screamed, and break
ing away, rushed along the treet, closely
followed by the man.
This man, when arrested, said: "I'm
Jack, the Ripper! All Whitcchapel is
looking for me! I have just arrived. I
intended to give myself up, as I have
alrtadly killed fifteen, and I'll yet com
plete the number if you let me go. You'd
better hang me by the neck till I'm dead
He had a big knife, and said his real
name was John Langhorn, aged 25,0f Lon
don. He is detained for further examina
tion.        </text>
      </result>
      
      <!-- 3) "The Whitechapel Fiend has Adapted a New But Effective Scheme" – Fort Worth Daily Gazette (Fort Worth, TX), December 22, 1888 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/XXXXXX/1888-12-22/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
Another Murder of a Woman in London
is Charged to the Whitechapel
Fiend Jack the Ripper
        </text>
      </result>
      
      <!-- 4) "Is It 'Jack the Ripper' Again?" – New York Tribune (New York, NY), December 22, 1888 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/XXXXXX/1888-12-22/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
IS IT "JACK THE RIPPER" AGAIN
IAN0THEK FALLEN WOMAN FOUND MiCRDlSREP
IN A PimrRB OF LONDON.
London, Dec. 21.?The body of a woman, wbo?-e
name li unknown, was found yea tend bf morning in Un
streets of Poplar, In the suburbs of London. An
empty vial lay alongside the b.idv, and the impres?
sion first formed wa* that the woman had committed
suicide. At the covonor's inquest lo-day, however,
the physicians who examined the bed] leettfied that
there were no signs of poison in the stomach, and de?
clared -heir belief that the woman had bass murdered
by strangulation. They said the condition of the
body Justified this belief, and In addition to that
there was a mark on the woman's neck which showi-?l
that a cmall cord had been Bad tightly around th Tba
woman was of low cha-ra-cte.r. What the lumv ti
found lt wa? fill warm. Il was lying in an __(en
thorough faire, ard there ls r.o poealbuitj that th?^
woman coule hav.. taloen her own life. Some persons
believe that her murderer ls Identical with thfl Wt-te
c ha pel ficml. wh/,, the-y think, has adopted .i
method of disposing of his v*,t.lms.        </text>
      </result>
      
      <!-- 5) "Cut Up The Corpse" – St. Paul Daily Globe (Saint Paul, MN), December 27, 1888 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/XXXXXX/1888-12-27/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
CUT UP TE CORPSE.
A Philadelphia Murderer Em
j ulates the Example of
Jack the Ripper.
He Dismembers His Victim
and Puts the Pieces
in Packages.
Forty Innocent Children Rav
ished by a Physician
in Escanaba.
Crazed by Grief, a Cincinnati
Jurist Slows Out His
Brains.        </text>
      </result>
      
      <!-- 6) "A Change of Base" – St. Paul Daily Globe (Saint Paul, MN), December 28, 1888 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/XXXXXX/1888-12-28/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
Jack the Ripper Sends Cold
Chills Up the Eacks of
Belgians.
Russia's Envoy to the Vati
can Hampered by a Lack
of Power.
Home, Dec. 28.— Mr. Gladstone, in a
letter to the Marquis Deriso. says that
the position of the pope is important
enough to merit intervention by inter
national arbitration. After remarking
that he promoted the Alabama arbitra
tion scheme, Sir. Gladstone adds that
"arbitration would possibly unlock a
difficult question, and the 'project has
his full and warm sympathy."
A CHANGE OF BASE.
Jack, the Ripper, Throws the
People of Brussels Into a Spasm
of Fear.
Special Cable to the Globe.
Brussels, Dec. 27.— This city has
been thrown into a ferment of excite
ment by the reception by prominent
people of cards and telegrams announc
ing the advent in the quaint old city of
the famous "Jack, the Kipper." of
Whitcchapel notoriety. King Leopold,
the prelect of police and the court min
isters are amomr the recipients of this
mysterious being's delicate attentions.
LACKS POWER TO ACT.        </text>
      </result>
      
      <!-- 7) "The Mania for Murder" – The Sun (New York, NY), January 5, 1889 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/XXXXXX/1889-01-05/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
The Mania for Murder
Tho English public a excited by tho occurrence
murders In different of the
currence of dllernt parts
mucr pa te
kingdom which bear so strong a likeness t
those committed by JACK tho Ripper that
they seem to b Imitations of his horrible
work A In tho Whltechapol murders the
bodies of the victims are mutilated The
killing seems to b dono from a sheer mania
for butchery none of the usual motives
being discoverable
I Is not at all Impossible that JACK the
Hipper has started a new school of murder
and murderers Human experience shows
that tho more morbid tho criminal manifes
tations the more likely they ore to stimulate
imitation hi other diseased natures Mania
breeds mania rather provokes It In minds i
dispse t insanity 0 one hysterical wo
man will set a whole hospital ward of women
wa
t screaming The notoriety of the Whit I
chapel murders brought them t tho atten
tion of that large number of persons whose i
moral and Intellectual balance Is most likely I
to bo and tho simple have
t b upset nd among they I
been and conversation the most engrossing subjectofthought
The conditions favorable t tho spread of
a mania for Imitation have therefore been
present and the circumstance that JACK
the Ripper has not been caught and punish
ed for his horrible crimes has undoubtedly
assisted in propagating a craze for killing
for Us own sake Even the Insane a de
terred from murder by dread of punishment
and fancied immunity from tho penalties
visited on the criminal becomes t them a
Incentive to crime
Tho failure of the London police t bring
tho Whlteohapel murderer to Justice s ex
traordinary In the history of crime is there
fore I terrible social misfortune It Is making
ing of him a hero and an example Morbid
minds a likely t bo upset entirely by
dwelling on his atrocities and his ability t
commit them many times over without de
tection Because ho I Inhuman a fiend In
the form of a man ho excites devilish pro
pensities uncontrollable In others except by
te fear of certain punishment
It I said by our police that oven hero In
Now York there has been much tcrrornmong
tho women of the street lest JACK tho Kipper
should appear In person or stimulate others
to engage In his horrible specialty The
alarm of those women Is not surprising But
In New York the career of such a murderer
would b short Because of that certainty
so generally understood wo are not likely
to havo Imitations of the
Imiatons Whltcchapol mur
ders though unless JACK the Ripper Is
brought to Justice they are likely t occur
In England until he ceases t bo a subject of
discussion and It
public dicusion curiosity        </text>
      </result>
      
      <!-- 8) "Jack the Ripper" – The Morning Call (San Francisco, CA), October 25, 1890 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/XXXXXX/1890-10-25/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
"JACK THE RIPPER."
Another Mysterious and Bru
tal Murder in London,
Tlie Mutilated Body of a Woman Dis
coVered in a Secluded Locality.
Ealfour Staris on a Tour of Investigation
Through the Western Counties
oi Ireland.
Special to The Morning Cam.
London, Oct. 24.— The"Jaek-the-Ptipper"
scare is on again to-uight. In a secluded
1 art if the South Ilampstead locality was
found the dead body of a woman whose
head had been nearly severed, while the
l dy showed kicks and bruises sufficient to
cause death. The victim was a woman of
low repute, and this was sufficient to start
the cry of "Jack the Ripper."        </text>
      </result>
      
      <!-- 9) "It's Jack the Ripper" – St. Paul Daily Globe (Saint Paul, MN), April 25, 1891 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/XXXXXX/1891-04-25/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
IT'S JACK THE RIPPER.
The Notorious London Butch
er Does a Regulation Job
in New York City.
A Dissolute Woman of the
Slums Murdered in Jack's
Inimitable Lcj-ie.
His Bloody Cross Is on the
Base of the Spine of the
Victim.
The Police Have a Good Des
cription of the Murderer
to Work On.
Netv York. April 24.— Now let the
police of New York prove their boasted
superiority over the police of London.
Jack the Kipper is here. He has done
his unspeakable work. His victim,
mangied as he mangled her predecessors
in the grim list in London, lies now as
he left her in the garret where the deed
was done. Further than that, the
weapon used has been found and is in
the hands of the police. But. more than
all. Jack the Ripper himself was
seen before he did his bloody
work The girl who saw him
is able to give a close
and clear description of him, and if
brought face to face with him can iden
tify him positively. The story of the
crime is horrible in its simplicity and in
its familiarity. Under different sur
roundings, and with modifications inci
dent to those surrounninsrs. it is an
exact repetition of the horrible atroci
ties of Whitechapel. The scene is in a
little dirty squalid room up on the fourth
aiid topmost rioor of a wretched lodging
house, known as the East River house,
and kept by one James Jennings.        </text>
      </result>
      
      <!-- 10) "Jack the Ripper's Mark" – The Sun (New York, NY), April 25, 1891 -->
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/XXXXXX/1891-04-25/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
JACK THE RIPPERS MARK
TllK rOVnOY CRIMES ISItTATKO Itf A
WATER STHIUtT ATI
After Butchering cmi Old hug ol tkeNtreta
the Murderer tteratehe a Cross Vpoa f
Her Bodr He was Ooaa Hoar Befbr
the Body wit Foandni IVeel Known
Thoachnnd the New York route have
Thnl Advnntnit Over Heotland Yard
lie Lets ntu Knllv Too and Onrrird
Away tkn Key of the XoomA Bad KM
Knonm as frcneby Aniona TkoM
Vader An tA Drag 2511 Cnat IK the
Low Kecorl Inapeetor Byrces Tka
the Field In ParaonBnntlnc In Prtea
ers CroavaxnBlnatlon
The painted bags who swarm on the rlvar
front between Itoosevelt and Catharine streets
havelost ono of their number An Imitator
Jack the flipper It not Jack himself butcharad
her on Thursday night and escaped at hl
leisure leaving her mutilated remains in the
wretched room hey had taken for tbenUtht
Last night a large force of police wore drat
glng the low resorts ot the neighborhood aid
Inspectors flumes and Williams war at tha
station house aquentlonlng the prisoner
They had found out who the murdered womaa
        </text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
